Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers ALBA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: General Subject Files, 1937-1990; 82537
  - Research Questionnaires: Medical Service Volunteers (Blank), undated; 82723 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Research Repository: Adelphi University, 1971; 82722 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Research Repository: Archivo General de Indias (Sevilla), undated, 1974; 82721 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Research Repository: Biblioteca Nacional and Central (Spain), 1941, 1971-1972; 82720 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence (includes undated FM notes/comments on the archives at Brandeis), undated, Oct 1970-Apr 1971; 82719 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor, May 1971-Jul 1971; 452276 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Aug 1971-Dec 1971; 82718 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1972-Mar 1972; 82717 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Apr 1971-Sep 1972; 452277 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Oct 1972-Dec 1972; 82716 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1973-Jul 1973; 82715 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Aug 1973-Dec 1973; 82714 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor (appointed as FM's research associate), Nov 30, 1973; 452267 (Box 25, Folder 3A)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jul 1974-Dec 1974; 82713 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1974-Jun 1974; 82712 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1975-Dec 1975; 82711 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, 1976; 82710 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, 1977; 82709 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, 1978-1985; 82708 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor (from FM, drafts and fragments), Undated; 452266 (Box 25, Folder 9A)
  - Research Repository: British Medical Association Library, 1972; 82707 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 1, undated; 82706 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 2, undated; 82705 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 3, undated; 82704 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 4, undated; 82703 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 5, undated; 82702 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 6, undated; 82701 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection: Guide and Research Correspondence, undated, 1963, 1972-1975; 82700 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), undated; 82699 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), 1936; 82698 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 1, 1937; 82697 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 2, 1937; 82696 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 3, 1937; 82695 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 1, 1938; 82694 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 2, 1938; 82693 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), 1939; 82692 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), 1940; 82691 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Research Repository: Hispanic Society of America, undated, 1971; 82690 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Research Repository: Hermoteca Municipal (Madrid), undated, 1970-1972; 82689 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Research Repository: Hoover Library, 1964-1978; 82688 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Research Repository: Imperial War Museum, undated; 82687 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Research Repository: Institut d'Historia dels Moviments d'Emanciopacio National I Social (Catalan Organization, Paris), 1970-1971; 82686 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Research Repository: International Institute for Social History, undated, 1983-1985; 82685 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Research Repository: Library of Congress: General, undated, 1970-1977; 82684 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Research Repository: Library of Congress: Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1977; 82683 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Research Repository: MacMasters University (Hamilton, Ontario), undated, 1971-1972; 82682 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Research Repository: McGill University, 1972; 82681 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Research Repository: National Archives and Records Service, undated, 1978-1985; 82680 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Research Repository: National Library of Medicine, undated, 1971-1978; 82679 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Research Repository: New York Academy of Medicine Library, undated, 1971, 1976; 82678 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Research Repository: New York Public Library: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1949-1970; 82677 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Research Repository: New York Public Library: McKelvy White Collection: Notes, undated; 82676 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Research Repository: New York Public Library: McKelvy White Collection: Pamphlet and Serials, undated; 82675 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Research Repository: Northwestern University, 1971; 82674 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Research Repository: Ohio Wesleyan University, undated, 1969-1971; 82673 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Research Repository: Salamanca Archives, undated, 1984; 82672 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Research Repository: Servicio Historico Militar, undated, 1971-1972; 82671 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Research Repository: United Nations Library, 1970-1971; 82670 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Research Repository: U.S. Army/U.S. Air Force: Joint Medical Library, 1976; 82669 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Research Repository: University of California at Berkeley (Bancroft Library), undated, 1966-1972; 82668 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Research Repository: University of California at San Diego, undated, 1971-1976; 82667 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Research Repository: Yale, 1977-1980; 82666 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Robeson, Paul, undated, 1979, 1984; 82665 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - "Romancero de Chichicastenango" (typescript copy with notes and introduction by the author, Rosa Hilda Zell, etc.), undated, 1967; 445266 (Box 26, Folder 31a)
  - Romania: Clippings, 1964-1982; 82664 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Small, Charles, undated, 1970-1978; 82663 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Soviet Union: Clippings, 1966-1975; 82662 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Soviet Union: Jews, undated, 1971-1974; 82661 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Spain: Alfonso XIII and Victoria Eugenia: Clippings, undated, 1941-1975; 82660 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Spain: Alfonso XIII: Pamphlet, 1927; 82659 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Spain: Alveriz de Toledo, Isabel, duquesa de Medina Sidonia: Clippings, 1967-1970; 82658 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Spain: Amnesty for Republicans: Clippings, 1976-1983; 82657 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Spain: Anarchists: Clippings, 1972-1981; 82656 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Spain: Andalucia, 1978-1982; 82655 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Spain: Arts and Culture: Clippings: Folder 1, 1966-1979; 82654 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Spain: Arts and Culture: Clippings: Folder 2, 1966-1979; 82653 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - Spain: Arts and Culture: Clippings: Folder 3, 1966-1979; 82652 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Spain: Arts and Culture: Clippings, 1980-1982; 82651 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Spain: Barcelona: Clippings, undated, 1971-1973; 82650 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Spain: Calvo Sotelo, Rafael: Clippings, 1974-1982; 82649 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Spain: Camacho, Marcelino: Clippings, 1970-1976; 82648 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Spain: Carillo, Santiago, 1971-1978; 82647 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Spain: Carlists: Clippings, 1968-1975; 82646 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Spain: Carrero Blanco, Luis: Clippings, 1973-1976; 82645 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Spain: Censorship: Clippings, 1968-1982; 82644 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Spain: Constitution: Clippings, 1977-1978; 82643 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Spain: European Relations, 1975-1981; 82642 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Spain: Falange: Clippings, 1969-1979; 82641 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Spain: Forest, Eva: Clippings, undated, 1975; 82640 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Spain: Fraga Iribarne, Manuel: Clippings, 1976; 82639 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Guidebooks and Souvenirs, undated, 1947-1986; 82638 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Spain: Juan Carlos: Clippings, 1968-1969; 82637 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Spain: Juan Carlos: Clippings, 1970-1973; 82636 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Spain: Juan Carlos: Clippings, 1974-1976; 82635 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Spain: Juan Carlos: Clippings, 1976- 1980; 82634 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Spain: Juan Carlos Coronation: Clippings, 1975; 82633 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Spain: Labor: Clippings, 1969-1973; 82632 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Spain: Lister, Enrique: Clippings, 1937, 1966-1981; 82631 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Spain: Martinez Bordiu Franco, Maria del Carmen: Clippings, 1972-1975; 82630 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Spain: Monarchy: Notes and Clippings, 1968-1976; 82629 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Spain: National Geographic Magazine devoted to Spanish Culture, Mar 1929; 82628 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Spain: Opus Dei: Clippings, 1969-1977; 82627 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Spain: Parliament: Clippings, 1969-1980; 82626 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, undated, 1940-1979; 82625 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, undated; 82624 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1939-1958; 82623 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1960-1964; 82622 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1967-1968; 82621 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1969; 82620 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1970-1971; 82619 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 1), 1972-1973; 82618 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 2), 1972-1973; 82617 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1974; 82616 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 1), 1975; 82615 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 2), 1975; 82614 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 3), 1975; 82613 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 1), 1976; 82612 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 2), 1976; 82611 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 1), 1977-1978; 82610 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 2), 1977-1978; 82609 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1979; 82608 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 1), 1980-1981; 82607 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings (Folder 2), 1980-1981; 82606 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1982; 82605 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Spain: Politics: Clippings, 1983-1987; 82604 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Spain: Relations with Mexico: Clippings, undated, 1968-1974; 82603 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Relations with Mexico: Clippings, 1975-1976; 82602 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Spain: Relations with Mexico: Clippings, 1977-1979; 82601 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Spain: Relations with Mexico: Clippings, 1980-1982; 82600 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Spain: Relations with Mexico: Portillo's Visit to Spain: Clippings, 1977; 82599 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Spain: Relations with Mexico: Portillo's Visit to Spain: Clippings, 1978-1981; 82598 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Spain: Relations with Soviet Union: Clippings, 1968-1979; 82597 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Spain: Religion, undated, 1938-1939, 1968-1982; 82596 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Spain: Socialist Party (PSOE): Clippings, 1971-1982; 82595 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Spain: Suarez, Adolfo: Clippings, 1977-1982; 82594 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Spain: Travel Maps, undated; 82593 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Spain: Travel Postcards, Tickets and Souvenirs, undated, 1947; 82592 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Spain: Union Centro Democratico: Clippings, 1978-1982; 82591 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Spain: U.S. Foreign Relations, 1936-1939, 1945-1977; 82590 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Spain: U.S. Foreign Relations: Clippings, 1966-1981; 82589 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Spain: Women's Issues: Clippings, 1972-1979; 82588 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Civil War: Bibliographic Sources, undated; 82587 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Civil War: Bibliographies: García Durán, Juan, undated; 82586 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Civil War: Book Reviews, undated, 1939-1979; 82585 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Civil War: Child Welfare, undated, 1938; 82584 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Civil War: Clippings, 1936-1939; 82583 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Spanish Civil War: Clippings, undated, 1942-1985; 82582 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Spanish Civil War: Graves, undated, 1990; 82581 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Civil War: International Brigade Directive on Rank, 1937; 82580 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners and Concentration Camps, undated, 1938-1939, 1980; 82579 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Civil War: Research Repositories, undated, 1970-1975; 82578 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Communist Party: Clippings, 1968-1982; 82577 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Spanish Communist Party Report on China, undated; 82576 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Cuisine, undated; 82575 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc. (includes Nancy Macdonald correspondence with FM), 1970-1982; 82574 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Spanish Writers: Clippings, 1935, 1969-1970; 82573 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Thomas, Norman, undated, 1971-1977; 82572 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Trotsky, Leon, 1979; 82571 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Committee for a Democratic Spain, 1976; 82570 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee, 1940-1941; 82569 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Vallejo, César: Clippings, undated, 1978; 82568 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Western Europese Conferentie Voor Spanje, 1971; 82567 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Tarazona: Training Camp, 1938, 1971; 82566 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Veterans: Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Notes and Clippings, undated, 1938-1976; 82565 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Veterans: Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans Living in Mexico, undated, 1940, 1970-1972; 82564 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Veterans: Cleveland Volunteers, undated; 82563 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Veterans: Pensions for Disabled Republican Soldiers, undated, 1940, 1973-1977; 82562 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Veterans: Re-entry Permits for Resident Aliens: Correspondence (photocopies), 1939; 82561 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Veterans: Wisconsin Volunteers, undated, 1970-1980; 82560 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Association with Medical Volunteers, undated, 1979-1983; 82559 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Barcelona Movement, undated, 1987; 82558 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Correspondence, Roberts, Leaflets, undated, 1948-1988; 82557 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): 40th Anniversary Program Honoring Women, undated, 1977; 82556 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1985-1987; 82555 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Florida Post, 1979; 82554 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): FM Critiques of, undated; 454204 (Box 29, Folder 37A)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Historical Commission, undated, 1967-1983; 82553 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): International Brigades Archive (Moscow) Controversy: Correspondence, undated, 1981; 82552 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Name (FM comments on "Brigade" vs. "Battalion" controversy), undated; 454203 (Box 29, Folder 39A)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Subversive Activities Control Board (SACB), undated, 1947-1980; 82551 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Veterans Recognition Campaign, undated, 1971, 1978; 82550 (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): West Coast (including FM dispute with), undated, 1962-1984; 82549 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Western Hemisphere Meeting: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1970-1971; 82548 (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Correspondence Requesting Participation, 1970; 82547 (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Anonymous; Altman, Jack; Amery, Al; Bailey, Thomas; Bowie, John, 1969-1971; 82546 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Cannon, Karl; Colodny, Robert; de Maio, Anthony; Felson, Milton, 1970; 82545 (Box 29, Folder 46)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Graeber, Kenneth; Groden, Daniel; Harris, Aaron; Hall, Harvey, 1970; 82544 (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Jordan, Frank; Kane, Larry; Keller, Fred; Koblick, John, 1970; 82543 (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Lockett, John; Lossowski, Vincent; MacLeod, Dan; Pacey, Donald, 1970; 82542 (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Perlman, Norman; Ross, Adolph; Siegel, Joseph; Sims, John, 1970-1971; 82541 (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Smith, Randall; Stamm, Morris; Yale, Stuart; Tivin, Isadore, 1970; 82540 (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Toney, Anthony; Valuch, Rudolph; Van der Schelling, Bart; Wesson, Neil, 1970; 82539 (Box 29, Folder 52)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Questionnaire for Wounded Vets: Wheeler, Bill; Wolff, Milton; Yellin, Jack; Ziedman, Frank, 1970; 82538 (Box 29, Folder 53)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda: Poetry and Notes, 454198 (Box 29, Folder 54)
- Series VI: Artifacts: Textiles and Pin, 1937; 82534
  Series VI. Artifacts: Textiles and Pin, ca. 1937. There are two items in this series: The black wool nurse's cape Martin wore in Spain, and a Medical Bureau pin - a gold cross surrounded by laurel leaves.
  - Spanish Civil War Nurse's Cape, 1937; 82536 (Box 30, Item 1)
  - Spanish Civil War Nurse's Pin, 1937; 82535 (Box 30, Item 2)
- Series VII: Duplicates, 1936-1984; 82527
  Series VII. Duplicates, 1936-1984. When archivists at Brandeis University initially inventoried the Fredericka Martin collection in 1991, five boxes of duplicate material (chiefly carbons and photocopies) were separated and retained. These boxes, which were transferred to New York University in January 2001, are shelved with the processed manuscript materials in Boxes 32-36; they are available for review upon request.
  - Duplicates, 1936-1984; 82533 (Box 31)
  - Duplicates, 1936-1984; 82532 (Box 32)
  - Duplicates, 1936-1984; 82531 (Box 33)
  - Duplicates, 1936-1984; 82530 (Box 34)
  - Duplicates, 1936-1984; 82529 (Box 35)
- Series VIII: Unprocessed Materials, undated; 553007
  - Unprocessed Materials, undated; 553008 (Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
- Series IX. 2015 Accretion
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists almost entirely of correspondence from the 1970s and 1980s to and from Martin regarding her research on the Abraham Lincoln Brigade and the nurses and medical personnel in the Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy. The series also includes a small number of photographs, some of which appear to date from the 1930s in Spain during the Spanish Civil War. Explanatory notes attached to various documents, groups of documents and folders were written by Tobyanne Berenberg, Martin's daughter.
  - Photographs, 1954; 593104 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Framed Photographs, undated; 593105 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Materials on Other Veterans, 1960-1979; 593106 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Theodore (Ted) Ryberg, 1972-1973; 593107 (Box 40, Folder 4-7)
  - Mollie Steimer and Semo Flechine, 1969-1981; 593108 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Doris Hayden, 1959-1969; 593109 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Wayne State University Group, 1980; 593110 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Mary Cunningham, 1970 September 15; 593111 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Charlotte Abbott, 1981-1982; 593112 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Alice Wexler, 1980; 593113 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Stacy Phillips, 1981; 593114 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Jane Wholey, 1977-1981; 593115 (Box 40, Flat-file 15)
  - Hill and Wang, 1960-1984; 593116 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, 1938-1989; 593117 (Box 40, Folder 17-22)
  - Moe Fishman Correspondence with Tobyanne Berenberg, 1971-1995; 593118 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and Clippings, 1964-2014; 593119 (Box 40, Folder 24-25)
- Series X. 2020 Accretion, 1930-2019; 1.5 linear feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 half manuscript boxes
  This accretion to the Fredericka Martin Papers consists of materials created and collected by Martin and her daughter TobyAnne Berenberg documenting Martin's experiences as a nurse in the Spanish Civil War, her life in Mexico, and her career as a writer. Materials include personal correspondence, diaries, biographical information about Martin, newspaper clippings on subjects of interest to Martin, and published writings. Many folders in this accretion contain an explanatory note by Berenberg describing the materials' significance in the context of Martin's life.
  - Aleut Language, 1946 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Articles by Martin in The American Indian, 1946, 1950 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information, 1930-2019 (Box 41, Box 2-8, Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Citizenship and Residency Controversies, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Courses Taught at Centro Intercultural de Documentacion (CIDOC), 1968-1976 (Box 41, Folder 10-11)
  - Crown Publishers -- Guide to Mexico, 1963-1970 (Box 41, Folder 12, Box 42, Folder 1-2)
  - Diary, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Economic Assistance, 1977, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Greenbelt, Maryland, 1939-1984 (Box 44, Folder 3-4)
  - How to Live And/Or Work in Mexico Typescript, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 6-8)
  - Immigration Documents for Mexico, 1954-1961 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Personal Correspondence -- General, 1967-1988 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)